Killian Jochen McShane

Computer Science Student

killian.jmcshane@gmail.com github.com/killianmcshane linkedin.com/in/killianmcshane in killianmcshane.github.io +44 7821745056

Third-year student of computer science at The University of Liverpool, specialising in artificial intelligence and data science. Proficient in R, Python, Java, SQL, and functional Haskell programming languages with experience using software development and data analysis tools such as Apache Ant and Tableau. I am highly IT and Mathematically literate, with a strong background in customer-facing roles.

Education

BSc (Hons) Computer Science

The University of Liverpool

09/2018 - Present

First Class (Expected)

Career

Customer Service Representative

The Royal Bank of Scotland

10/2017 - 03/2018

Belfast

- High-pressure environment with heavy call gueues, and complex verbiage.
- Teamwork, exceeding KPI expectations and preventing escalations was necessary to succeed.
- Asking pertinent questions and empathetically delivering help was key to resolving issues quickly.

Customer Service Representative Teleperformance UK

10/2016 - 04/2017

- Handled and managed customer complaints.
- Discussing payment options, credit management and answering general enquiries.
- Building rapport with customers.

Data Analysis Spring Internship FM Environmental

04/2015

- First-hand experience of the duties of an engineer.
- Analysed and processed friction and fluid calculations.
- Graphed insights from data analysis using Excel to relay information to engineers.

Languages

References

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

Associate Lecturer (UoL)

German Professional Working Proficiency Mrs Kay Arrowsmith 0151 794 2000

Mr Jed Goldsag Line Manager (RBS) 0345 724 2424

Skills



Achievements

Founder & President of The Data Science and Artificial Intelligence Society at The University of Liverpool

I manage the society's conduct and the organisation of the group as a whole. My leadership involves chairing meetings, attracting funding, and managing relationships with stakeholders.

BT Young Scientist Boot Camp (2015)

Selected for and won the competition. Lead a team of 5 individuals through the development lifecycle of a new product.

Interests

Boxing Running		Mathe	matics
Deep Learni	ing Bi	g Data	Crypto & Blockchain

Projects

- Exploratory Data Analysis on Branch Sales (Tableau) A presentation of insights from my analysis of raw CSV sales data.
- Bank Statement Classification & Data Analysis (Python) A Deep Neural (NLP) Network I trained on 12500 transactions. Includes an in-depth presentation of insights and predictions.
- Automated Build Deployment & Testing (Apache Ant) Build deployment using Apache Ant, Java, an XML build file, and JUnit.
- Short-term Stock Price Prediction Web-app (Python, JS) Prediction using an LSTM Neural Network & Twitter Sentiment Analysis.

...and many more on my GitHub profile.